Andrew R. Jones

★ andrewrayjones.com **②** Austin, TX **▲** andrewrayjones@gmail.com **in** jonesan2 **८** 512-461-1312

Profile

I'm a full-stack software engineer with a passion for problem solving and experience in the Ruby and JavaScript ecosystems. I'm transitioning to software after eight years of teaching high school physics. I co-created Gander, an open-source review app solution that automatically deploys a full-stack preview application with every pull request.

Experience

Co-Creator & Software Engineer, Gander

2021

gander-framework.github.io ♂

- Co-created an open-source, drop-in solution for automatically deploying full-stack review apps from pull requests
- · Contributed to design of core architecture with three components: AWS infrastructure, GitHub workflows, and CLI
- Contributed to design of review app build solution, leveraging Cloud Native Buildpacks to generate Docker images
- Led routing implementation, using AWS application load balancer, target registration, and CNAME records
- Led writing and testing of Python/Django demo and contributed to testing for Golang, Ruby, and JavaScript demos
- Automated provisioning of AWS infrastructure with bash scripts through GitHub Actions
- Researched and defended AWS infrastructure decisions, evaluating tradeoffs with respect to ECS, EC2, Fargate, Elastic File System, load balancers, and subnets
- Co-authored technical case study exploring Gander's design challenges and solutions

Software Engineer, Self-Employed

2018 - 2021

- Cello: Trello-like collaboration app built for MongoDB with a Node/Express backend and a React/Redux frontend
- RequestTub: React/Express app for capturing and monitoring webhooks, built using Socket.IO and with PostgreSQL storage
- Todos: Sinatra todo management app, built for PostgreSQL and using Erb

Teacher, Advanced Physics & Engineering, Hays CISD

2013 - 2021 | Buda, TX

- Teacher of the Year Nominee; selected 14 times by a student from the Top 10% as their most influential teacher
- Launched high school robotics program; Coached UIL state finalist robotics team

Skills

Languages

JavaScript, Ruby, SQL, HTML, CSS, Go

AWS Cloud

Amazon VPC, Amazon ECS, AWS Fargate, Elastic File System (EFS), Elastic Container Registry (ECR), Application Load Balancer, IAM, AWS CLI, CloudFormation

Frameworks

React.js, Express.js, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails

Technologies

Docker, Git/GitHub, GitHub Actions, Cloud Native Buildpacks, HTTP, WebSocket, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST APIs, Redux, Heroku, Handlebars, Erb, Shell Scripting

Education

Launch School 2020 – 2021

Multi-year mastery-based learning curriculum for software engineering | launchschool.com/employers 🛮

Ph.D., Hebrew Language and Literature, University of Toronto

2008 - 2015 | Toronto, Canada

M.A., Christian Studies, Regent College

2004 - 2007 | Vancouver, Canada

B.S., Computer Engineering, with distinction, Purdue University

1997 - 2001 | West Lafayette, IN